Subtitling made
possible by Acorn Media
[suspenseful music]
♪♪
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
- No. it's good. It's good.
- It's all right.
It's all right.
- Nice out there.
- Yeah.
Are you all right? You
took that hit pretty hard.
- Oh. I think I'll survive.
[laughs]
[tapping]
- Damn it. Driscoll. stop that!
- It's called control.
I'd hazard you could
learn some of that.
- As could you. Eddie.
You almost injured three
of your teammates today.
- The Shamrocks. the Victorias.
they come at you in waves.
We need to be ready.
- [sighs]
- Captain.
- I said stop that.
- He's still smarting
after being made
to look the fool on the ice.
- Watch your mouth. Driscoll.
- Easy. boys.
We all play for the same side.
- Not all of us.
Driscoll here doesn't
play for the team.
He plays for himself.
- And you're lucky to have me.
- You care nothing
for the science
and strategies of this game.
- Science my arse.
I skate like the devil
and get the puck
past the goalkeeper.
which I haven't
seen you doing lately.
- Take it easy. Take it easy.
Captain. you all right?
- What is wrong with you?
- Simpson. man.
Come on. wake up.
- [groaning]
- Sorry. Simpson.
I didn't think.
- That's your problem. Eddie.
- Looks like we
could all use a drink.
The Mongoose and Ferret?
- I'll be there presently.
Ow.
- Crabapple.
- Eddie Driscoll.
Good to see you.
- Well. aren't you a
sight for sore eyes.
Sorry I kept you
waiting. Georgie boy.
I had a little errand to run.
- Quite all right.
- It's on the house. sir.
- And my friend here?
- Of course.
- Not bad for a working
man. eh. George?
- You know. I
read in The Gazette
that somebody by your name
had joined the Wellingtons.
Thank you. I was
sure it would be you.
- Been here a month.
Look at you now.
a big city copper.
- And a mystery novelist.
I published a novel.
I brought you an
autographed copy.
Now. I signed it
to you and Lydia.
I wasn't sure if...
- Married last year.
- Married?
That's fantastic.
I'm very happy for you both.
- Well. what can I say?
I guess the best man won.
[suspenseful music]
♪♪
- His name is Archibald Simpson.
He was found at 6:15
by one of his teammates.
Mr. Jerome Bradley.
- I've yet to take his
internal temperature.
so I can't give you a
precise time of death.
- And the cause?
- Uncertain.
but he appears to
have suffered an injury
to the back of the head.
- According to Mr. Bradley.
sir. the victim was involved
in a dustup after the
afternoon practice.
- Where is this Mr. Bradley?
- He's just outside.
- Bring him in. Henry.
- Jerome Bradley?
- You know him?
- When I was younger.
- Emily.
- Hello. Jerome.
- Mr. Bradley. I understand
that Mr. Simpson
was involved in
a scuffle earlier.
- Yes. he took a punch
and bashed his head open
on that post there.
There was quite a lot of blood.
He came to. though.
- What time was this?
- 5:00 or thereabouts.
You think that's
what killed him?
- If he suffered
subdural bleeding.
death could have been
delayed an hour or more.
- Who delivered the punch?
- Eddie Driscoll is his name.
- Where might I
find this Mr. Driscoll?
- At the Mongoose and Ferret.
- Eddie Driscoll?
Pleasure to meet you.
Buy you a drink?
- I never say no to another.
- Really gave it to
those boys from Ottawa.
- That I did.
Now. if you'll excuse me.
I'm talking to my
good friend here.
Well. been a happy
man since I discovered
the true love of my life.
Or should I say.
since it found me?
- It?
- Hockey of course.
- Detective Murdoch.
Oh. please. make
the acquaintance
of my good friend
Eddie Driscoll.
- It's a pleasure to
meet you. Mr. Driscoll.
I wonder if you
could accompany me
to Station House number 4.
- The station? Why?
- I'm placing you under
arrest for manslaughter.
- He came at me first. George.
I simply clocked him back.
He was alive when we left him.
- It will all get sorted out.
Do you want me to
contact Lydia for you?
- No.
I won't have her see me here.
- Maybe a solicitor. then?
- You think I'll be needing one?
- The players all agreed to
meet at a tavern after the practice.
but Simpson never arrived.
- Who saw him last?
- A Samuel Farrell.
but he claims that Simpson
was very much
alive and conversive
when he last saw him.
- Murdoch. if this is
just a matter of fisticuffs.
don't you think that a
manslaughter charge
is a little harsh?
- Sir. a man is dead
as a direct consequence
of a violent assault.
By definition. that
is manslaughter.
- If you ask me. they
should lock him up.
- Why?
- Driscoll is nothing
more than a thug.
a lowlife ruffian.
and he hardly belongs
in a sport for gentlemen.
- This scuffle in
the locker room.
who started it?
- Well. Simpson. I suppose.
but Eddie Driscoll
certainly brought it
to a conclusion. didn't he?
- Who's in charge here?
- That would be me.
And who might you be?
- Langston Wallace.
I'm the owner of
the Wellingtons.
Manslaughter? That's ridiculous.
Eddie's my best player.
- He's your best player.
therefore. he couldn't possibly
have committed manslaughter?
- All he did was punch
him in the jaw once.
- Were you even in the
room when it occurred?
- I heard enough to
know it was an accident.
and Simpson was up.
walking. talking right after
like nothing had happened.
I spoke to him myself.
- All points for a
jury to deliberate.
- You don't understand.
You see. the Toronto Wellies
are about the challenge
the Montreal Shamrocks
for Lord Stanley's
coveted trophy.
There's to be an
announcement at a luncheon.
- I don't see the relevance.
- The relevance is this.
With Eddie. we win the Cup.
Without him. we lose.
- I appreciate your position.
- I don't think you do.
You see. no team from
Toronto has ever won the Cup.
a situation that
your chief constable
has an active
interest in rectifying.
- A fan. is he?
- Our biggest.
So if you appreciate
your position. you...
- Listen to me.
I don't give a toss
which team flag
Chief Constable
Giles likes to fly.
- Sir.
- And I don't take
kindly to threats.
- Inspector Brackenreid.
Langston. my apologies.
- Your apologies are
unnecessary. Percival.
- So what exactly
is going on here?
- I've arrested Eddie Driscoll
on the charge of manslaughter.
- On what grounds?
- He assaulted Mr. Simpson.
and later Mr. Simpson
died of his injuries.
- Langston. let me
talk with my men here.
I'll keep you appraised.
- Thank you.
I'll wait for you.
- Sir. under the circumstances.
we're required by law to
charge him with manslaughter.
- By law. is it?
Strange how a confessed murderer
can slip freely from your cells.
but a young man who
lands an unlucky punch.
well. the letter of the law
simply must be applied.
- Are you suggesting
it shouldn't?
- Do you know for
a fact that Simpson
died from that punch?
- Dr. Grace has yet to
complete her postmortem but...
- I have to go to an important
luncheon. as does Mr. Wallace.
When I return. you will
present me with proof
that Eddie Driscoll
has committed a crime.
or you will release him.
- Dr. Grace.
Have you confirmed
the cause of death?
- I have indeed.
Take a look at this.
This is the injury he received
when his head hit the post.
This is the blow
that killed him.
- Are you saying he
received another blow
after the incident
in the locker room?
- Based on the bruising.
I'd estimate the fatal
blow was delivered
about half an hour later.
which conforms to my best
estimate for a time of death.
- And what time would that be?
- Approximately 6:00.
- Which means this
was no accidental death
caused by a locker room scuffle.
- Gentlemen. our
final order of business
will be to strike a committee
to see if we can
find a unity of rules
for each hockey organization.
I pledge that next year
all hockey leagues
will follow the example
of our Ontario
Hockey Association
and adopt the use
of the hockey net.
[applause]
- It's not the rules we
should worry about.
It's the damn professionals.
- There won't be professionals
as long as John Ross
Robertson is in charge.
But we may lose some of our
best players to the Americans.
- Oh. it's our game.
The Yanks will never embrace it.
Besides. if you pay a
man to play a game.
who will work the factories?
- Hmm.
[glass clinking]
I have an announcement
to make. gentlemen. if I may.
As you all know.
the other day in
a tragic accident.
we lost Archie Simpson.
the revered captain
of our great team.
The Iron Dukes of Toronto.
the Toronto Wellingtons.
well. we still have the best
hockey team in all the land.
[cheers. murmuring]
Yes. yes. And we
are going to prove it.
Our newly appointed
captain. Mr. Jerome Bradley.
will lead the Toronto
Wellingtons' charge
as we challenge the Montreal
Shamrocks for the Cup.
[applause]
- You mean Lord
Stanley's punch bowl.
[laughter]
The closest you will ever
get to the Cup. Wallace.
is when we hoist it
over your head in victory.
- We'll see about
that. McLaughlin.
Archie Simpson will
be watching over us
as we show the Shamrocks
who plays the best hockey.
[crowd murmuring]
Well. what do you
think of our chances?
- Greatly improved.
This Driscoll fellow is
a crackerjack player.
- Mr. Wallace.
- Yes. he is.
- Excuse me.
What's the meaning
of this intrusion?
- Chief Constable. I
regret to inform you
that Mr. Simpson's
death was no accident.
It was murder.
Mr. Wallace. I'm afraid your
run for the Cup will have to wait.
- It's about time. I'd say.
- Mr. Driscoll.
- Yes?
- Would you sign this for me?
- You gonna give it
to the Shamrocks?
- Do my best.
- Move along now. son.
- You see that. George?
Your detective
Murdoch arrested a hero.
- I'm sorry. Eddie.
Detective Murdoch
did what was required.
- Be that as it may. I
missed a full practice.
- Eddie. a man is dead.
- It's all very sad.
but it wasn't me that
killed him. was it?
Besides. he was
hardly good enough
to be worth all this fuss.
- Dinner is the
least you owe me.
You did. after all. leave me
standing bereft at the altar.
- That's not exactly
true. Jerome.
I informed you well
before the wedding day.
- The invitations were
already printed and addressed.
- But not yet mailed out.
- Nonetheless. all expected
to be dancing with us
at our wedding.
- I never meant to
hurt or humiliate you.
But there is nothing
to be regained
by attempting to rekindle that
which was never meant to be.
- I agree. Emily. Let's
let bygones be bygones.
Please indulge me with your
company over dinner tonight.
Just as old friends.
That's what we are now. right?
- All right.
- Detective.
- Dr. Grace.
why are you entertaining
a potential suspect here?
- I didn't invite
him. Detective.
and I certainly wasn't
entertaining him.
- Under no circumstances
is a suspect to be allowed
anywhere near evidence.
- It won't happen again.
- You have something for me?
- I believe it may be
able to help identify
the murder weapon.
I found these in
Mr. Simpson's hair.
- Wood slivers.
- Exactly.
You are looking for
a long. thin implement
made of wood.
- I believe I know where I
might be able to find one.
Thank you. Doctor.
- A hockey stick.
Sir. it pains me that
such a joyful apparatus
could be used in
such a terrible way.
- Not as much as it pains
me that they cleaned up
this locker room.
Have a look at this. George.
Simpson was found here
with his back to his locker.
- It would be hard to strike
him in the back of the head
if he was there. sir.
- Exactly.
I believe his body
was moved here.
- Why not just leave
him on the floor?
- Clearly. the killer wanted
us to think that Simpson died
of his earlier injury.
- [chuckling] Sir. look at this.
- What?
- Oh. these skate marks.
It appears that one of
the best skaters in this city
walks like a duck
when he's off the ice.
- Have you finished
labeling the sticks. George?
- Yes. sir.
They're all marked
according to their owner.
- Shall we?
- What have you got. Murdoch?
- Sir. I believe one
of these hockey sticks
to be the murder weapon.
The task before us is
to figure out which one.
- How are you going to do that?
- Through chemi-phosphoro
luminescence. sir.
You see. sir. this compound
will emit a blue glow
when it's oxidized.
In this case. the iron
and the hemoglobin
will act as the catalyst.
The effect should only
last about half a minute.
but it will be long
enough to tell us
which one of these sticks
has been exposed to blood.
Now. sir. if you could
turn out the light.
[lamp buzzing]
- Bloody hell.
It's a tough sport.
I'll give it that.
- Any one of these sticks
could be the murder weapon.
- What are you
doing in the dark?
- What have you. George?
- Sir. McTavish.
Danton. and McKenna
were all at the
Mongoose and Ferret
between 5:30 and 7:00.
The barkeep vouches
for their presence.
Jerome Bradley was at
the Mongoose and Ferret
but left to go to the rink.
Apparently. he'd
left his wallet there.
- Mr. Bradley claims to
have found the body at 6:15.
He could have arrived sooner.
so he remains on the list.
- Fair enough.
Now. Farrell claims that
he stayed after the practice
to work on his wrist shot
but that he was on his way
to the Mongoose and Ferret
when the murder occurred.
- No alibi. then.
- Finally. Mr. Wallace was
on his way home at 6:00.
but that's yet to be confirmed.
- What about Driscoll?
- He was supposed
to stop by. sir.
to give an account of
his whereabouts. but...
- Driscoll had a
dustup with the victim.
He might be good for it.
- Now. sirs. I know that
Eddie can seem full of himself.
but I can vouch
for his character.
- You keep your distance
from your pal. Crabtree.
As long as Driscoll
remains a suspect.
we can't risk giving
him any information
that would compromise
this investigation.
- Sir. I would never.
- Just remember your
obligations as an officer of the law.
Understood?
- Sir.
- What about Farrell?
He was once a team forward.
right wing. if I'm not mistaken.
- If you say so.
- Well. when Simpson
was brought from Ottawa.
Farrell had to give up his spot.
That would have given him a
bone to pick with Simpson. surely.
- Enough to kill him. sir?
It's just a game.
- You're not much interested
in sports. are you. Murdoch?
If you were. you'd know
that there's no such thing
as "just a game."
- I had no idea you
were such an enthusiast.
- It's not rugby. but it'll do.
- I've always enjoyed
playing the game.
but to sit and watch
the game being played
seems like a waste of time.
- It's a product of
our age. Murdoch.
More leisure time.
People looking for
ways to spend it.
You should try it sometime.
- Could read a book.
- Mm.
- [clears throat]
Enjoy it while
you can. Driscoll.
You'll soon be back
shoveling horse dung.
- [laughing]
Doubt that.
I'm the future.
- Eddie. we have to leave.
- I'd love to buy a round
for the house before we go.
Aw. you're an angel.
- Mm-hmm.
- One of the many perks
of being the Wellington's
ace in the hole.
- Eddie. you're
drunk as a skunk.
- Let me buy you one.
- No. no. no.
I'm not even supposed
to be talking to you.
- Then why are you?
- Because I'm your friend.
- So who does your
Detective Murdoch
think committed the murder?
[laughing]
- Eddie. you were supposed...
You were supposed to come in
and give an account
of your whereabouts.
- My whereabouts are
nobody else's business.
- No one's business.
Eddie. this is a murder
investigation. man.
Now. when you met
me after that practice.
you were late.
Where were you?
- You suspect me?
- I don't...
- Eddie. we have to go.
- What's this? What about Lydia?
- We're only young
once. Georgie boy.
Time's fleeing!
Have fun while we can.
[chuckles]
- Excuse me. gentlemen.
A moment of your time?
- We're busy.
- Oh. it's you.
This lanky chap's
a police officer.
- Really?
Well. I'm tremendously reassured
as to the safety of our streets.
- You're Samuel Farrell.
- I am indeed.
- Do either you suspect
that anybody on the team
might have a grudge
against Simpson?
- His name was
Mr. Archibald
Simpson. Constable.
and he was as fine
a man as you'd meet.
- A gentleman if ever
I've encountered one.
He'd intended enlisting
after season's end
to fight for our mother
country against the Boers.
He was a highly
principled fellow.
- Yes. unlike your lout friend.
Do you want to know
who hated Archie?
It was Eddie Driscoll.
- Archie made it clear
that Driscoll didn't belong
in a gentleman's game.
- And Eddie killed him for it.
Now. if you'll excuse me.
I have an assignation
with a young lady.
- Between you and me?
I wanted Eddie on the team.
He made us contenders.
If you want someone
with a grudge.
look no further than
our new captain.
- Good night. barkeep.
Same time tomorrow.
- Good night. Mr. Bradley.
- Bradley?
[ominous music]
♪♪
- We should have called
the wedding off sooner.
but I was trying to
make everyone happy...
Everyone except myself.
- Well. I plan to win you back.
- Jerome. you promised you
weren't going to bring that up.
- And you promised
you'd marry me.
So I suppose we're both liars.
You're coming back to me.
It's just a matter of time.
You don't have a
choice in the matter.
I'll win the Cup. and then
I'm gonna win you back.
Now. shall we order desert?
- I really should
be going. Jerome.
I rise early.
Thank you for a lovely dinner.
Good-bye.
- Good-bye? I
don't think so. Emily.
I'll be seeing you
sooner than you think.
- Good-bye. Jerome.
- [clears throat]
[snaps fingers]
- Jerome Bradley?
- Sir. when the Wellingtons'
first captain retired last year.
Bradley was set
to become captain.
Then they brought
Simpson in from Ottawa.
Simpson insisted that
he become captain.
and Wallace capitulated.
- Ah. that must have
made Mr. Bradley upset.
- So upset that he quit. sir.
He only rejoined last month
when he found out the team
was gonna challenge for the Cup.
- But still. that's hardly
a reason to kill Simpson.
- Well. think about it. sir.
If Jerome Bradley was
captain and they won.
he would be the first
ever Ontario athlete
to hoist Lord Stanley's mug.
And. sir. he's had a few
run-ins with the Constabulary.
No convictions. of course.
His high-priced lawyers
have to seen to that.
needless to say.
- George. you seem to
have it in for this Bradley.
- No. sir. I don't.
Well. perhaps I do.
I know he's well-bred and
from a good family and all that.
but he's...
He sort of lords it
over you. doesn't he?
- Bring him in.
- What's this?
- It would appear
you have a history
of violence. Mr. Bradley.
- I have a history of
getting into punch-ups
when I've had a few.
- I would like to note that my
client has never been convicted.
- You have the nerve to suggest
that this predisposes
me to murder?
- Did you or did
you not quit the team
when Mr. Simpson became captain?
- I quit because I
could not stand by
and watch the team I loved
sullied by the likes
of Eddie Driscoll.
Archie felt the same way.
He and Mr. Wallace
almost came to blows over it.
- When was this?
- Last week in
Mr. Wallace's office.
I don't know what they
were shouting about.
but I heard Eddie's
name loud and clear.
If anyone killed Archie.
it was probably that
low-class farm boy.
You call yourself a lawyer?
Then why do I have
to do all the talking?
- Bloody toff. I
wish he was guilty.
- I'd like to know what
Simpson and Wallace
were having words about.
- Tread lightly. Murdoch.
or Giles will be all
over us like a rash.
- Sir. Chief Constable
Giles is an honest policeman.
If he holds any malice for us.
it's because we've earned it.
What were you and
Mr. Simpson arguing about?
- Strategy.
Proper deployment of players.
- Specifically.
- Simpson was unhappy
with Eddie Driscoll's
place on the team.
as were a number of players.
- And why was that?
By all accounts. he was
your most talented player.
- Oh. yes. he was that.
but he wasn't one of them.
If I could speak frankly.
most of the players on the team
thought Driscoll beneath them.
They only tolerated him
because of his abilities.
- And your captain
shared that view?
- No. Simpson didn't care
about Driscoll's background.
He was somewhat of a
republican in that sense.
He disliked Driscoll
because of the manner
in which he played the game.
- And he wanted
him off the team?
- Well. that's what we
were arguing about.
I told him it was
none of his business
to be issuing me ultimatums.
But Simpson said it
was either him or Eddie.
- Did Eddie Driscoll know that
Simpson wanted him dropped?
- Well. he certainly
didn't keep it a secret.
Now. I'm due for
my supper. Detective.
Can you let yourself out?
- Yes. of course.
- Good.
- Aha.
George. bring in...
Samuel Farrell.
- I wasn't in Mr. Wallace's
office that day.
- Then how do you explain
this piece of your stick
that we found on the floor
in Mr. Wallace's office?
- I have no idea.
Anybody could have grabbed
it. either by mistake or by intent.
- Where were you at the
time of the murder. Mr. Farrell?
- As I recall. I stayed
late after practice.
I went for a walk
and then to the tavern.
- Do you always take a
walk after a hard practice?
- A stroll cools me down.
- Did anyone see you?
- I have no idea.
- So you have no alibi
for the time of the murder?
- All you have is a shard
of my stick. Detective.
I don't see that
I need an alibi.
So if you'll excuse me.
- Not so fast. Mr. Farrell.
You'll have plenty
of time to remember
who saw you strolling
when you're cooling off
in one of our cells.
- Mr. Farrell. how tall are you?
- What's it to you?
- Answer him.
- I'm 5'8".
My low center of gravity
gives me an advantage.
- Hodge. escort
Mr. Farrell to the cells.
What were you thinking?
- Sir. Mr. Farrell is the
shortest player on his team.
If I can determine the
height of the killer...
- It can prove it was him.
- Right here. ma'am.
- George Crabtree.
- Lydia.
- Hello. George.
It's lovely to see you.
- Well. you as well.
What brings you here?
- I was asked to
make a statement
as to Eddie's whereabouts
at a particular time.
which I've now done.
- Of course. So he was with you?
- That's correct.
Immediately after practice.
right when poor
Mr. Simpson was killed.
- Right. well. thank
you for coming in.
Lydia. sit down.
- Thank you.
I know you and Eddie have
been chumming around.
- Well. I've seen him.
- George. is he still
being true to me?
- As far as I can tell.
he's still the same
old Eddie Driscoll.
- So you haven't seen anything?
- Well. all I've seen. Lydia.
is that he has many admirers.
- He's always had that.
- Mm.
- Well. look at you.
big city policeman.
An important man.
- Important. I don't know...
- George. I need you
to get me six melons.
- Uh. sir. they're
out of season.
- Right. Six pumpkins. then.
- Yes. sir.
Some of my tasks are
more menial than others.
- Thank you. George.
Right. then.
- The angle of impact
is too high on the skull.
Still too high.
Perfect.
Now. given the difference
between your height
and the height of this pumpkin.
and subtracting that
from Mr. Simpson's height.
we can conclude that
the killer is 5'10" tall.
- Or maybe he
was taller than that
but crouching when he attacked.
- That's a good point. George.
We can't determine
the maximum height;
only the minimum.
- And if the killer
was at least 5'10"...
- That means Samuel
Farrell can't be our killer.
- Bloody hell. I
was sure it was him.
No alibi. It was
his hockey stick.
- Well. at the very least. sir.
this narrows our
list of suspects.
- So what next?
- I still think he was
killed in Wallace's office.
- Do you think Wallace did it?
- Not necessarily.
Mr. Wallace kept his
office door unlocked.
It does raise the
question. however:
what was Simpson
doing in Wallace's office?
What have you. George?
- Sir. I was going
through Simpson's effects
as you asked.
Amongst the other
paraphernalia was this:
a return train ticket to Ottawa
dated the 29th and
30th of November.
- That's only a few days ago.
- Why would he go up to Ottawa?
- Well. I don't know. sir.
but there's something else
written on the back of it there.
- J.R.R.
- John Ross Robertson?
- Why. yes. very good. sir.
Perhaps 221 is his
Parliament Hill office number.
- Looks like you're going
to Ottawa. me old mucker.
[mysterious music]
- Yes. Simpson did make
an appointment to see me.
He lodged a very
troubling complaint.
- And that was?
- Mr. Simpson maintained
that Langston Wallace
was paying one of his
players for his services.
- What would the consequence
be if that proved true?
- Immediate and
permanent ejection
from the Ontario
Hockey Association.
- I see.
What was your reaction to
Mr. Simpson's allegation?
- I told him that if he wanted
an investigation launched.
he would need to provide
some hard evidence.
- Had he any?
- Nothing but hearsay.
While I knew Simpson
to be an honest man.
an investigation at this point
would inevitably
have forestalled
the Wellingtons'
challenge for the Cup.
for which there's been
so much anticipation.
- Yes. So you did
nothing further?
- I made some
discreet inquiries.
- Did you find any basis for
Mr. Simpson's suspicions?
- I found no cause to
pursue the matter further.
- Did he mention the
name of the player
he suspected was being paid?
- He did.
- And?
- With all due
respect. Detective.
a man's good name
and the reputation
of a fine hockey team
is on the line here.
- I assure you. I will handle
all aspects of this conversation
with the utmost discretion.
- This game is being taken
over by rogues and capitalists.
Detective Murdoch.
I'm doing all in
my power to stop it.
I do hope you are on side.
- Sir.
The name.
- Eddie Driscoll.
- Eddie Driscoll is being paid?
- That's what
Mr. Simpson believed.
but he didn't have the proof.
- Perhaps that's why
Simpson was in Wallace's office
the night he was killed.
- Well. sir. if he did find
the proof he was looking for.
that would certainly
spell the end
of Wallace's grand
ambitions for his team.
- Well. forget the Cup.
This would get the Wellingtons
kicked out of the league.
- Still. sir. it seems
absurd that an individual
would actually pay
others to play a game.
- It's more and more
commonplace. Murdoch.
It's even happening with
the football back home.
Oh. bloody hell.
- Chief Constable.
- I just had a message
from Langston Wallace.
You're investigating a
rumor that the Wellingtons
have been employing
a paid professional?
- We are. sir.
- But you must know
what that means.
It would be the end of the team.
- Sir. I'm only looking into it
as it pertains to
our investigation.
Should Langston Wallace
prove to be innocent of murder.
I see no reason
why the allegations
should come to light.
- No.
No. if it's true. it must
be brought to light.
- Sir?
- There's no greater
stain on the face of hockey
than the specter
of professionalism.
- Greater than
cold-blooded murder?
- Yes. I admit that
Langston Wallace
has a strong motivation
to try to keep this
from getting out.
Perhaps at the expense
of a young man's life.
Get to the bottom
of it. Murdoch.
Langston may be my friend.
but if he's broken the law...
- Yes. sir. I will.
- You see. this
is the difference
between us. gentlemen.
I don't let my personal
friendships come between me
and my sworn obligations.
- I've been looking at
your ledger. Mr. Wallace.
You make a significant
amount of money
charging admission to
Wellingtons hockey games.
- I do all right.
- You would make even more
if you were the owner
of a championship team.
Acquiring Eddie Driscoll
made that a very real possibility.
- I'm already a
wealthy man. Murdoch.
I certainly am not in
need of the gate recipes
the team produces.
- You deny paying
Eddie Driscoll. then.
- Of course I deny it.
Professionalism would
be the end of hockey.
The gate recipes would all
end up going to the players
as teams tried to
outbid each other.
- Tell me. how does a
man like Eddie Driscoll
pay his room and board?
He has no job.
but he seems to have
plenty of money to spend.
- It's not my concern.
- Then why does your
ledger list a $5 debit
for miscellaneous
expenses for every game?
- Because I have
miscellaneous expenses.
- Of exactly $5.
every game.
and only since Eddie
Driscoll began playing
for the Wellingtons?
According to the rules of the
Ontario Hockey Association.
payment of a player
is strictly forbidden.
If it were to come out
that you have been
paying Eddie Driscoll.
you would forfeit your
chances at the Stanley trophy.
- Cup. Murdoch. It's a cup.
- Cup.
I believe Simpson
stumbled upon this ledger
and realized it was
the proof he needed.
and you killed him for it.
- Look at me. Murdoch.
Do you really think
that a man my age
is capable of killing
a young sportsman
in the prime of his life?
- So if it's not Wallace.
that just leaves
Driscoll and
Bradley as suspects.
- But Eddie
Driscoll had an alibi
confirmed by his wife.
- Sirs...
- What is it?
- Oh. I wouldn't pull much
truck in Lydia Driscoll's words.
I'm quite sure Eddie
coerced her to lie for him.
- Damn it. Crabtree.
- George.
- Why didn't you
mention that earlier?
- Because I think he's an
adulterer. not a murderer.
And I think he had
his wife lie for him
because he couldn't get an alibi
from the woman
he was actually with.
- Bloody hell. Crabtree.
- He wouldn't have
killed anybody. sir.
I'm sure of that.
- Bring him in.
- No. sir. Bring
the wife in first.
- I wasn't lying.
My husband was
with me after practice.
- He came all the way
home after practice
and then went the same distance
all the way back to the tavern?
- He was being a good husband.
What's wrong with that?
Why don't you believe me?
- You were right.
George. She was lying.
Arrest Eddie Driscoll.
- Sir.
- [laughing]
- Eddie. I've been
sent to arrest you.
- Again?
- Just come with me.
- Eddie Driscoll. who is this.
this floozy you're with?
- You dare call me a floozy?
- I—I'm not with anybody.
- You were with
her. weren't you?
You bastard.
You made me lie for you.
And to you. George
Crabtree. of all people.
I thought you were my friend.
I ask you directly. and you
as good as lied to my face.
- Lydia— - You
should be ashamed.
- Did you bring
her here. George?
- No. I didn't bring
her here. Eddie.
She must have followed
me from the station.
She is a good woman.
and she lied for you.
And I tried to believe her.
You better have a good
story as to where you were
when Archie Simpson was killed.
- I can't. Eddie. You know that.
- Unfortunately for
you. Mr. Driscoll.
your alibi no longer holds.
Your wife has
retracted her statement.
I think that Mr. Wallace
had been paying you.
Mr. Simpson found out about
it. and you murdered him.
- You're wrong.
I don't care who
knew I was being paid.
If I don't play for this
team. I can play for another.
They pay people in America.
Better money than I make here.
- All right.
Where were you the
evening of the murder?
- I was with a woman.
- Her name?
- A gentleman doesn't...
- Her name. sir.
- Felicity Wallace.
- Langston Wallace's
granddaughter.
- But she won't admit
to being with me.
- What time did you leave her?
- I don't remember.
- Where did you go after your...
assignation?
- To the Mongoose and
Ferret. where I met George.
- Constable Crabtree stated
that you met him at 6:15.
That would have given you 15
minutes to commit the murder
and make it back to the tavern.
- I was at a bookmaker's
shop before I met George.
- For what reason?
- I was betting on myself
to take my team to victory
against the Shamrocks.
My lady friend fronted
me the $50 I was to receive
as a bonus if the
Wellingtons won the Cup.
The Shamrocks may
be heavy favorites.
but the bookmakers know
nothing about what I can do.
My $50 will soon net me $500.
- I care neither about your
game or your wagering.
I'm looking for a murderer.
- I didn't kill Simpson.
and that's the truth.
- [gasps]
- Hello. my darling.
- Jerome. you scared
the daylights out of me.
- Oh. I'm so sorry. my dearest.
Far from my intention.
- You're drunk.
- What of it?
- You can't be here. Jerome.
You must leave immediately.
or I'll have
Constable Crabtree...
- Oh. Constable Crabtree!
Come and save you.
[laughing]
That's a joke if
I've ever heard one.
Now. into my arms. my dearest.
- This behavior is
unacceptable. Jerome.
- Unacceptable?
You have the nerve
to say that to me?
I offered to bring a
lowly working-class girl
up to my station.
- I have apologized for that.
There's nothing
further for me to do.
- You can reverse
that earlier error.
- It wasn't an error.
The mistake would have been
to go through with the wedding.
- You ungrateful whore.
- Ah!
Take your leave. sir.
or I'll have to arrest you.
- This is none of your
business. Now leave us to it.
- Get out of here!
- [grunting]
- Get up!
You're under arrest for
assaulting a police officer
and a lady.
I apologize for the
mess. Dr. Grace.
Good morning. sir.
Eddie Driscoll's
alibi checks out.
He laid the bet at exactly 6:00.
He wasn't the only one
who put some money
on the Wellingtons. sir.
And not just $50.
- Mr. Farrell.
You're a gambling
man. it would seem.
- I've made a few bets.
- But you've lost most of them.
In fact. you had to
borrow the $2.000
to place on the Cup challenge.
- I'd have made good on it.
- How?
You've squandered
all of your money.
You have no profession.
Of course. with ten-to-one odds.
you stood to make
a small fortune
if the Wellingtons won.
But that would have required
that Eddie Driscoll play.
And had it been discovered
that Eddie was being paid.
you would have been ruined.
According to your statement.
you stayed after
the team practice
to work on your wrist shot.
That's when you saw Simpson
going into Wallace's office.
isn't it?
And you got curious.
- Wallace is paying Eddie. Sam.
I got the proof right here.
- You panicked.
But then you remembered
Simpson's earlier injury
and realized you could
use it to your advantage.
At first. I didn't
think it was you.
because you're not tall enough.
But you would have been. had
you been wearing hockey skates.
- That's all speculation.
You have no proof.
- And you have no alibi.
Your stick was the
murder weapon.
Your motive is clear.
On the face of it. it looks
like murder in the first degree.
But should you confess
in your own words
that this was a
rash. unplanned act.
you may be spared the noose.
- I was way over
my head in debt.
and I was counting
on the Wellingtons' win
to square it off.
I couldn't afford
for us to lose.
I had to.
It would have
disgraced my family.
But I've done that
now. haven't I?
- Game on. lads!
- Yeah. George. yeah.
- Take us out. Worseley.
- Ooh. hoo. hoo. hoo.
- Oh. blood hell.
Worseley. Watch that. lad.
- Right. then. George.
Better mind yourself.
I am going to make
you look the fool.
- Oh. we'll see about that. sir.
- Get it. George!
[cheering]
- What was that
you were saying. sir?
- Nice move. George.
- Who taught you
that. Eddie Driscoll?
- No. sir. I taught
him that one.
Although no one could do it
like Constable Deke. eh. boys?
[laughter]
- Whoa!
- Oh!
- Through my legs. Murdoch.
- Thank you for
letting that one in. sir.
- Oh.
- Don't worry. Inspector.
I'm just letting him
build some confidence.
[horse neighing]
- Wagon!
- Wagon.
So where's Eddie now. George?
- Sir. he's in Pittsburgh
earning $6 a game.
- $6? That's madness.
- He thinks he'll
earn more. sir.
Maybe up to $10 somewhere else.
- Bloody hell.
- $10.
I doubt that. George.
But still. getting paid to play.
he's a lucky man.
- All right. game on!
- Play.
[dog whimpering]
- Oh!
- Yes!
Subtitling made
possible by Acorn Media
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm